credulous: adj. 轻信的
Lesson 36. A chance in a million. We are less credulous than we used to be. In the 19th century,
第36课。一百万的机会。我们不比以前的信仰。在19世纪，
a novelist would bring his story to a conclusion by presenting his readers with a series of
小说家会通过向读者展示一系列的一系列故事来结束他的故事
improbable: adj. 不大可能的, obscure: adj. 不起眼的
coincidences. Most of them wildly improbable. Readers happily accepted the fact that an obscure
巧合。他们中的大多数非常不可能。读者高兴地接受了一个晦涩的事实
presume: v.   假定
maid servant was really the hero's mother. A long-lost brother, who was presumed dead,
女仆仆人确实是英雄的母亲。一个被假定死了的久违的兄弟
wickedly: adv. 心眼坏地，居心叵测地, plot: v.   密谋, downfall: n.   倒台，垮台
was really alive all the time and wickedly plotting to bring about the hero's downfall.
一直都活着，邪恶地计划使英雄的垮台。
naive: adj. 天真的, unacceptable: adj. 不能接受的
And so on, modern readers would find such naive solution totally unacceptable. Yet, in real life,
等等，现代读者会发现这种天真的解决方案完全无法接受。然而，在现实生活中，
conspire: v.   （事件）巧合促成
circumstances do sometimes conspire to bring about coincidences which anyone but a 19th.
情况有时确实共同实现了19日以外的任何人的巧合。
incredible: adj. 难以置信的
Century novelist would find incredible. When I was a boy, my grandfather told me how a German taxi driver,
世纪小说家会发现不可思议。当我还是个男孩的时候，我的祖父告诉我，德国出租车司机如何
Franz Busman, found a brother who was thought to have been killed 20 years before.
弗朗兹·布曼（Franz Busman）发现了一个兄弟，他被认为在20年前被杀。
While on a walking tour with his wife, he stooped to talk to a workman. After they had gone on,
与妻子一起徒步旅行时，他弯下腰与一个工人交谈。他们继续前进，
Mrs. Busman commented on the workman's close resemblance to her husband and even suggested that he
布曼夫人评论了工人与丈夫的密切相似之处，甚至建议他
scorn: n.   嘲弄，挖苦
might be his brother. Franz poured scorn on the idea, pointing out that his brother had been
可能是他的兄弟。弗朗兹（Franz）嘲笑这个想法，指出他的兄弟已经
acquaint: v.   使了解
killed in action during the war. Though Mrs. Busman fully acquainted with this story, she thought
战争期间行动中被杀。尽管布曼太太完全熟悉这个故事，但她认为
that there was a chance in a million that she might be right. A few days later, she sent a boy
一百万的机会她可能是对的。几天后，她派了一个男孩
to the workman to ask him if his name was Hans Busman. Needless to say, the man's name was
向工人问他，他的名字是否叫汉斯·布曼（Hans Busman）。不用说，这个人的名字是
reunite: v.   使团聚
Hans Busman and he really was Franz's long-lost brother. When the brothers were reunited,
汉斯·布曼（Hans Busman）和他确实是弗朗兹（Franz）久的久违的兄弟。当兄弟们团聚时，
Hans explained how it was that he was still alive. After having been wounded towards the end of the war,
汉斯解释了他还活着的情况。在战争结束时受伤后，
he had been sent to hospital and was separated from his unit. The hospital had been bombed and
他被送往医院，并与他的单位分开。医院被轰炸了，
Hans had made his way back into Western Germany on foot. Meanwhile, his unit was lost and all records
汉斯步行回到德国。同时，他的单位丢失了，所有记录
of him had been destroyed. Hans returned to his family home, but the house had been bombed and
他中的中断被摧毁了。汉斯回到了他的家中，但房子被轰炸了，
no one in the neighborhood knew what had become of the inhabitants, assuming that his family had
假设他的家人有
been killed during an air raid. Hans settled down in a village 50 miles away where he had remained
在一次空袭中被杀。汉斯定居在50英里外的一个村庄
ever since.
从那以后。